Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, David H. Kurtzman (Acting), Administrative Files, 1966-1967 UA.2.10.1966-1967
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Humanities Division (Box 16, Folder 137)
  Request for a building; Fine Arts dissertations; Slavic Department; Tuesday Musical Club
- H (General) (Box 16, Folder 138)
  Heald and Hobson and other correspondence
- Industrial Hygiene Foundation (Box 16, Folder 139)
  Cooperative arrangement with GSPH
- Instruction: Disciplines (Box 16, Folder 140-146)
  Evaluations and recommendations, 1956-58; Correspondence from Radiation Laboratory; Plan to reorganize basic disciplines into Three divisions, 1956 Classics, English; Fine Arts Promotions; Music, Philosophy and Speech; Liberal Arts; Biology, Biophysics; Chemistry, Earth & planetary sciences, Mathematics; Physics, Psychology, Radiation laboratory
- Instruction: Disciplines (Box 17, Folder 147-151)
  East Asia, German, Romance Languages and Literatures, Slavic Studies; Anthropology, Economics, Geography, History; Political Science and Sociology; Physical Education, School of General Studies
  Access Restrictions
  Some files in Boxes 16-19 are restricted.
- Instruction: Professions (Box 17, Folder 152-155)
  Administrative Science Center; Business Administration; Education; Engineering
- Instruction: Professions (Box 18, Folder 156-161)
  Law, Library School, Mines, Public Affairs, Retailing, Social Work
- Instruction: Health Professions (Box 18, Folder 162-174)
  Dentistry, Medicine: Anatomy, Medicine: Anesthesiology, Medicine: Biochemistry, Medicine: Clinical Science and Microbiology, Medicine, Medicine: Obstetrics and Orthopedics, Medicine: Pathology, Medicine: Pediatrics, Physiology & Pharmacology, Medicine: Psychiatry; Medicine: Radiology and Surgery; Medicine: General, Nursing
- Instruction: Health Professions (Box 19, Folder 175-176)
  Pharmacy; Public Health
- Instruction: Supporting Services, Planning and Development (Box 19, Folder 177)
- Instruction: Organized Activities (Box 19, Folder 178-180)
  Athletics: Flood lights for playing field & parking lot; Summary of receipts of the Department; Budget for Stadium & Field House repairs; Library: About budgets; personnel; departmental libraries, 1955-56; Dean of men, women, Counseling, Registrar, Admissions, Chaplain: Some correspondence; salaries, budgets
- Instruction: Research (Box 19, Folder 181-184)
  Medical; Public Health; Office of Vice Chancellor of Medical Center
- Instruction: Budget Working papers (Box 19, Folder 185)
  No Subnote Content
- Inter-Institutional Research (Box 19, Folder 186)
  A catalog of intercollegiate cooperation in Pittsburgh, comp. by Dr. Leslie W. Ross and Dr. Lily Detchen. Spring 1966; Institutional Research Unit-plan for data collection, analysis & reporting system within Office of Planning
- International Association of Universities (Box 19, Folder 187)
  Reports for 1964-66; Dropped membership
- International Education Act (Box 19, Folder 188)
  Preparing the University to negotiate for funds. 1967; a copy of the Act
- International Programs (Box 19, Folder 189)
  Report, 1967; Residence program-Latin America; Ford Foundation annual report, 1965; International Studies program organized, 1966; C.E.T.T. program (Center for study, research and international exchanges. 43p.
- International Dimensions Program (Box 19, Folder 190)
  Comparative communism: an inter-university teaching and research program, 1966; (filed in 15/11-B)
- Intracom (Box 20, Folder 191)
  Organization for Pitt, 1967
- Invitations, Dinners and Guest Lists, 1957-1966 (Box 20, Folder 192-194)
- Invitations, Dinners and Guest Lists, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 195)
- I (General) (Box 21, Folder 196)
  Industrial Hygiene Foundation; International Education Exchange; Other correspondence.
- Johnstown Campus (Box 21, Folder 197)
  New Campus fund drive, 1962-65; Johnstown Advisory Board; Special, Johnstown Advisory Council; Appalachia Funds for Johnstown Campus
- J (General) (Box 22, Folder 198)
- Knowledge Availability Center (Box 22, Folder 199)
  Conference on new technology materials; Correspondence on agreements
- Kurtzman, David H. (Box 22, Folder 200-204)
  Speaking engagements completed; Column for Pitt News; Speeches, 1966 Personal correspondence A-M Personal correspondence N-Z Kurtzman, David H. Invitations accepted Kurtzman, David H. Invitations regretted
- Kurtzman, David H. Personal Files (Box 23, Folder 205)
  Oakland Chamber of Commerce "Man of the Year" award 10/2/1966 and "Citizen of the Week" award; South American trip 2/25/1967-3/15/1967; Congratulatory letters (acknowledgements); Honorary degree-Temple University, February 9, 1967
- K (General) (Box 23, Folder 206)
- Latin American Studies, Center for (Box 23, Folder 207)
- Law, School of (Box 23, Folder 208)
  Board of Visitors for Law School; Search Committee for Dean; Report of School submitted to the University Study Committee, August 1965
- Learning Research and Development Center (Box 23, Folder 209)
  Advisory Board; Board of Visitors
- Liberal Arts, School of (Box 23, Folder 210)
  Report on the School of Liberal Arts for the academic year, 1965-66; Reflections on the graduate student in undergraduate instruction; Academic objectives and the development of the lower campus, 1967, by Dr. James A. Kehl; Undergraduate Business study
- Library and Information Sciences, Graduate School of (Box 23, Folder 211)
  Review of Graduate Ph.D. program; Andrew Osborne, Professor
- Libraries, University (Box 23, Folder 212)
  1967/68 budget (notebook); Centralization of library administration; Progress report to the Council of Deans from Dr. Stone; Monthly report to the Chancellor, 1965-67; Plan for a Divisional library system; Development program for the libraries; Library Cooperative Group activities; Commuting students in Pittsburgh zone (chart); Priorities for Collection Development; Commons Room as a Reserve Book Reading Room
- LITE Program (Box 24, Folder 213)
  Legal Information Through Electronics; Health Law Center & Aspen Corporation collaboration on computer retrieval of legal information; Response to a complaint from former employees of Health Law Center
- Linguistics, Department of General (Box 24, Folder 214)
- Litchfield, Edward R. (Chancellor, 1955-65) (Box 24, Folder 215)
  Contents moved to Ch. Litchfield's files #216 and to Ch. Crawford's files #1.
- Log, 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 216)
- Lothrop Street Garage (Box 24, Folder 217)
  University Health Center Garage (Public Parking Authority) 1967; Child Guidance building & Blood Bank
- Lutheran Oakland Cemetery (Box 24, Folder 218)
  Proposed purchase from First Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church for construction of dormitories, 1963; Remains and burial records removed to Mt Royal Cemetery according to pastor of the church, 2/28/78; Some correspondence moved to Physical Plant file.
- L(General) (Box 24, Folder 219)
- Mailing List (Box 25, Folder 220)
  Regional campuses (Advisory boards; Agencies; University of Pittsburgh Board of Trustees; Government mailing list; University Health Center; Political list; Administrative officers of the University
- Maps of the University (Box 25, Folder 221)
- Martin, Park H (Box 25, Folder 222)
  Correspondence as Consultant for physical plant planning
- Medicine, School of (Box 25, Folder 223)
  New curriculum for M.D.'s; Health Center-Recommendation for sharing of electronic data processing facilities (35 p.); Hofman, Klaus, Jonas E. Salk Commonwealth Professor of Experimental medicine; Planning; Central Pharmacy Agreement, (1966) Sabbatical leaves; Clinical Research; Transfer of Pharmacy to Eye & Ear Hospital, 1966
- Mellon Pitt Carnegie Corporation (Box 25, Folder 224)
  Correspondence; Minutes; Treasurer's report; Standard Practices Procedure for safeguarding classified information
- Mellon Charitable Trust Grant, Department of Neurology (Box 25, Folder 225)
- Mellon Institute (Box 25, Folder 226)
- Mellon Physics Laboratory (Box 25, Folder 227)
  Old Mellon Institute changed to Allen Hall after Professor Alexander J. Allen
- Mellon Professors (Box 26, Folder 228-241)
  FF 228: Andrew Mellon FF 229: Biophysics FF 230: Classics FF 231: Comparative literature FF 232: English FF 233: Fine Arts FF 234: History FF 235: Mathematics FF 236: Modern Languages FF 237: Music FF 238: Philosophy FF 239: Physics FF 240: Romance Languages FF 241: Social anthropology
- Merlin Foundation (Box 26, Folder 242)
  Organizational meeting; Bylaws, 1965
- Military Science, Department of (Box 26, Folder 243)
  Correspondence 1965-67; R.O.T.C. history and statistics, 1954-66
- Mining Engineering (Box 26, Folder 244)
  Files related to the dissolution of the Department.
- M (General) (Box 26, Folder 245)
  "A Management Information System for the University of Pittsburgh; Correspondence: Mellon, R.K., Magee, Man of the Year, Manpower Research; Mathematics Department, Men's Glee Club, Menzies visit, Monnett family in Iran, and others.
- NAACP (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People) (Box 27, Folder 246)
  Correspondence; formal complaints, Medical School; Statistics on employees
- National Aeronautics and Space Administration (Box 27, Folder 247)
  Correspondence; Pamphlet; Proposed plan of action submitted to establish a Center of Education, Research, and Advisory Services in Public Administration as a part of the University of Pittsburgh Space Program; NASA facilities grant no. NsG (F)-13 Final report, 1965; Space Research Coordination Center; Proposal for Predoctoral research training grants, 1965
- National Science Foundation (Box 27, Folder 248)
  Grant Proposals, 1965-67
- National Technical Institute for the Deaf (Box 27, Folder 249)
  Proposal
- Nationality Rooms (Box 27, Folder 250)
  Refinishing the English Room; Nationality Council, Spring meeting, 1966
- Natural Science Facility (Box 27, Folder 251)
  Phase I and II, Correspondence (Crawford Hall)
- Natural Sciences, Division of (Box 27, Folder 252)
  Merger of two departments; Biophysics and Microbiology; Want to have a radio transmitter in the Airglow Observatory, Laurel Ridge; A Five-year science development plan for the Division, 1966
- Nike Control Site (Plum Boro) (Box 27, Folder 253)
  Proposal for re-use.
- Nursing, School of (Box 27, Folder 254)
  Reorganization and Baccalaureate Program; Report of the Nursing Study Committee, August 1966
- N (General) (Box 28, Folder 255)
  Correspondence, alphabetical
- Oakland Medical Center Garage (Box 28, Folder 256)
- Oceanography (British Virgin Islands) (Box 28, Folder 257)
  Correspondence concerning SABA (ship); Scaife grant; Oceanography project 1966-67
- Office Equipment (Box 28, Folder 258)
- Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 28, Folder 259)
  Community Action Program, project prepared by the University, 1966
- O (General) (Box 28, Folder 260)
  Oakland Corporation; O'Hara Parking Garage; ODK, etc
- Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities (Box 28, Folder 261)
  Minutes; Newsletters; Annual meetings
- Parking (Box 29, Folder 262)
  Parking Board of Appeal; Correspondence about lack of space and parking tickets & towing.
- Patents, University policy on, 1961, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 263)
- Peace Corps (Box 29, Folder 264)
  Correspondence; Congressional presentation, 1967. (May 1966)
- Pennsylvania, Commonwealth of (Box 29, Folder 265)
  Report to the Special Task Force of the appropriations Committee…of the House of Representatives April 4, 1967; Organization of the Pennsylvania Department of Public Instruction, December 1966; Statement on government of colleges and universities; Legislative bulletins, September 30, 1966 and October 7, 1966; Senate Resolution to keep Communists off campuses, 1965
- Pennsylvania Loyalty Act, 1956-1965 (Box 29, Folder 266)
- Pennsylvania State Education Association (Box 29, Folder 267)
  Annual conference, 1966; "Relation of the state to higher education in Pennsylvania, 1776-1874", by Warren Bosset Freuchtel, 1965 (dissertation); "Patterns of appropriations for institutions of higher education by the General Assembly of Pennsylvania, 1955-1966", by William A. Cornell, 1966; Preparation of the College teacher, by Everett Walters, 1966; Pennsylvania's master plan for higher education
- Pennsylvania State University (Box 29, Folder 268)
  'Report of the Committee on the institutional cooperation with recommendations attached", 1967; Pennsylvania. State Technical Services Act of 1965; Knowledge Availability Systems Center; Space and technology transfer, 1965
- Personnel (Box 29, Folder 269)
  Report of personnel activities, 1967; Faculty home purchase plan-five year report, 1966; Scholarships
- Pharmacy, School of (Box 29, Folder 270)
  Report on, by American Council on Pharmaceutical Education, 1966
- Philosophy Department (Box 29, Folder 271)
- Philosophy of Science, Center for the (Box 29, Folder 272)
  Letter from Hanson
- Physical Education Department (Box 29, Folder 273)
  1961-67 correspondence; Carlson Memorial Garden, dedication of; Playing fields; Physical Education Building, phase II, 1963
- Physical Plant (Box 30, Folder 274)
  Chemistry building on State Hall location, 1967; Construction projects since 1957 (as of April 25, 1966) School of Engineering building delay of opening; Bellefield Boiler Committee; Space availability; University planning, 1966; May 16, 1966 meeting concerning new buildings and money problems; Political Science floor in Cathedral of Learning 1966; Police protection; Heinz Chapel lighting
- Pitt News (Box 30, Folder 275)
  1967 correspondence; Acting Chancellor Kurtzman's article on the Carnegie-Mellon University merger
- Physics Department (Box 30, Folder 276)
  Airglow Observatory expense, 1965
- Pittsburgh College and University Business Officers Association (Box 30, Folder 277)
  Reports of meetings, 1965; On Data Processing, location for dead storage for library; Inter-institutional co-operation
- Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education, Meeting, February 16, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 278)
- Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education, Meetings, September 13, 1966 and May 2, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 279)
- Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education (Box 30, Folder 280)
- Pittsburgh Theological Seminary (Box 30, Folder 281)
  Cooperative Ph.D. program in the Study of Religion
- Planning, Assistant to the Chancellor for (Box 30, Folder 282)
  Edison Montgomery; New organization chart, 1967; Enrollment model for 10 years, 1966
- Policy Planning and Coordinating Committee (Box 30, Folder 283)
  Interuniversity Teaching and Research Program
- Policy Papers (Box 30, Folder 284)
  Patents, Conflict of Interest, Academic Integrity, Latin American Studies, Faculty Titles and others
- Planning, Vice Chancellor for (Montgomery) (Box 31, Folder 285)
  International Education Bill, 1966; Conflict of interest in government sponsored research, 1966; Athletics Cost Study; Survey of undergraduate students who resigned from the University of Pittsburgh in 1963/64 and 1965; Anna Moody Browne room, disposition of the books and furnishings (3 memos) 1965; Faculty-Board of Trustee relationships, 1965; Confidential memo "Faculty concerning economics"; Suggested budgetary policies and financial procedures, June 1965, 28 p.; Class hour analysis for a random sample of Freshman and Senior students, June 1965; Entering Freshman class, Fall Trimester, 1964, a descriptive and comparative study, May 1965
- Playing Fields (Box 31, Folder 286)
- Police Department (Box 31, Folder 287)
- Political Science, Department of (Box 31, Folder 288)
- Population Unit, Graduate School of Public Health (Box 31, Folder 289)
- Portraits, Brackenridge (Box 31, Folder 290)
- President's Report to the Legislature, Guidelines for (Box 31, Folder 291)
- Professional Schools Complex-Common Facilities Building(David L. Lawrence Hall) (Box 31, Folder 292)
- Professions, Vice Chancellor for (Van Dusen) (Box 31, Folder 293)
  Salary problems; Development problems for the University; Weaknesses in the University's printing program; Elmer Kaelin degree issue; Reorganization considerations
- Project Talent (Box 31, Folder 294)
  Contract with the University, 1966
- Protein Research Laboratory (Box 31, Folder 295)
  Plans, 1966; Memos from Klaus Hofmann; Paper: "Man-made enzymes: a goal for the future", by Klaus Hofmann; Need for more space; Report of the activities of the Laboratory; Biographical outline of Klaus Hofmann' Studies on polypeptides, 5 pts.; Bibliography of writing
- Pulbic Health, Graduate School of (Box 31, Folder 296-298)
  Funds to finance addition to School Building; Report on goals and activities of the Graduate School of Public Health, 1966; Policy decisions; Proposed revision of curriculum; Proposed University Population Center; Health Law Center
- Public Instruction, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of (Box 32, Folder 299)
  Evaluation of undergraduate teacher education, 1966; Report of Institutions of Higher Education, PA 1966; Accreditation for certain Engineering coursers; Summary report: Higher Education Invitational Conference On Intergroup Relations, February 3, 1966
- Public and International Affairs, School of (Box 32, Folder 300-300A)
  First Institute on/Executive Management for Senior Military Officials, Handbook, 1967; Institute on Applied Quantitative Techniques in sectoral planning, 1967; Donald C. Stone – House at 4200 Centre leased for him by the University (V.C. for Business Affairs) The University paid part of the rent; Urban regeneration; Board of Visitors
- Public Relations, Director of (Box 32, Folder 301)
  Name changed to Department of News & Publications, September 16, 1966; Future publicity on Pitt's financial situation, September 29, 1965
- Public Works Engineering and Administration, Graduate Center for (Box 32, Folder 302)
  Graduate Center for Public Works Engineering and Administration, 1967/68, New department); Statement for Public Works Congress on September 14, 1966; Proposed Center for Public Works, June 1966
- Purchasing and Office Supplies (Box 33, Folder 303)
  O'Hara Township Land, Standardized stationery; Bus Service; Library furniture, Switchboard
- P(General) (Box 33, Folder 304)
  Use of drugs questionnaire, 1966; Pittsburgh Regional Physical Fitness Program, 1966; Pittsburgh Chamber Music Society sponsored by University; Pittsburgh Sanitary Engineering Conference, 1967; Message to the "Polaris"; Polish Library in Paris; Price, Waterhouse & Co. - - Program to improve the University's financial function; Phi Beta Kappa Memoriam to Crawford
- Radiation Safety Committee (Box 33, Folder 305)
- Regional Campuses (Box 33, Folder 306-307)
  Business procedure for each; House expenses; Budgets and expenses; Organization chart; Policy Manual
- Regional Council for International Education (Box 33, Folder 308)
- Registrar (Box 33, Folder 309)
- Ruskin Apartments (Box 33, Folder 310)
- R (General) (Box 33, Folder 311)
- Salk Hall Dedication (Box 33, Folder 312)
- Security (Box 33, Folder 313)
- Secretary of the University (Box 33, Folder 314)
- Senate, University (Box 33, Folder 315)
- Senate, University (Box 34, Folder 316)
  Budget Policies Committee; Trustee Gwilym Price's statement to Council of Senate September 13, 1965 in reference to the University's financial situation
- Social Club Dues (Box 34, Folder 317)
- Social Sciences, Division of (Box 34, Folder 318-319)
  Resignation of Richard Park, Dean of Div.; Search for new Dean; A proposal for Social Sciences by Charles H. Peake; Center For Latin American Studies Certificate Program; Activities of the departments, September 1, 1964-August 31, 1965
- Social Work, School of (Box 34, Folder 320)
- Speech and Theater Arts, Department of (Box 34, Folder 321)
  Letters concerning the resignation of Dr. Ralph Allen from the Theatre; Letters & communications concerning Dr. Jack Matthews, who had been asked to join another University, 1967
- State Planning Board (Box 34, Folder 322)
  Building program, 1967
- Student Affairs, Dean of (Rush and Critchfield) (Box 34, Folder 323)
  Pennsylvania Resident for State-relatedness; Correspondence concerning dormitories; Questions from the Chancellor-Student meeting on April 6, 1967; I.D. card; Draft of "Miss Rush retires from Pitt Administrative Post"; Towers dormitories-question of names; Activities fee for graduate students; I.D. card; University fee; Parents Weekend Brochure
- Student Demonstrations (Box 34, Folder 324)
- Student Health Service (Box 34, Folder 325)
- Student Housing (Box 34, Folder 326)
- Student Records (Registrar) (Box 34, Folder 327)
- Student Union (Box 34, Folder 328)
  I.D. Card; Repairs; Pamphlet: Guide to services and facilities; Student Activities Calendar; Usage report
- S (General) (Box 34, Folder 329)
- Temple University (Box 35, Folder 330)
  Paul Anderson
- TIAA-CREF (Box 35, Folder 331)
- Titusville Campus (Box 35, Folder 332)
  Advisory Board, 1963-65; Fund raising campaign; Need for another dormitory
- Treadway Inn, Proposal for Boundary Street site (Box 35, Folder 333)
- Treasurer (Box 35, Folder 334)
  Retirement of G.S. Rupp; Reassignment of duties; Purchase of properties; Mayflower Apts.; Lutheran Cemetery
- Trimester System (Box 35, Folder 335)
  University of Michigan's study; David Landy's Calendar Study, 1966; Trimester vs. Semester plus Summer School; Adopted in Fall 1959
- Tuition (Box 35, Folder 336)
  Resolution for the approval of various changes in tuition and fee schedule, 1967/68; Simplified fee structure; Memo on policies concerning billing of new tuition fee
- T (General) (Box 35, Folder 337)
  Theta Chi Fraternity-Gwilym A. Price as recipient of First Annual Stanton C. Crawford Memorial Award, 1966; Theta Chi proposal for distinguished service Award
- Undergraduate Professional Program (Box 35, Folder 338)
  Report of Ad Hoc Committee on possible new programs, May 1966
- United Fund of Allegheny County (Box 35, Folder 339)
  Amounts pledged, 1965, 1966; Predecessor of United Way of Allegheny County (1974)
- University Counseling Center (Box 35, Folder 340)
  Broad cultural changes to which the urban university must respond; by Warren Hill; Cultural dehumanization and campus discontent, by Warren Hill
- University News and Publications (Box 35, Folder 341)
  Outline for Annual Report (since university is state-related); Mrs. Ann Loffer's letter about art work; Proposal for expanding public relations activities, by Ketchum MacLeod & Grove, Inc.; Public Relations name change
- University of Pittsburgh Press (Box 35, Folder 342)
  Correspondence concerning proposed republication of Daniel Long's Pittsburgh Memoranda; Projection of space needed; Memo from the Publications Committee to the Senate Council; Report of a visit to the University of Pittsburgh Press, by Bruce Denbo (Association of American University Presses, Inc.) 1966
- University Study Committee (Box 35, Folder 343)
  Role of the faculty in the future development of the University of Pittsburgh – Faculty of Medicine; File contains memos on the role of the faculty in the future development of the University, the Wells Committee and the Allegheny Community College; Also 0/2/1
- Unusual Letters (Box 35, Folder 344)
- U (General) (Box 35, Folder 345)
  United Nations Association of Pittsburgh meeting October 1966; United National Seminar on Urbanization, 1966; United Negro Protest Committee, February 1966; University Council of Graduate Study meeting, 1966; material from Associated Students from the University of California in Berkeley; Urban Affairs Seminar, 1966
- V (General) (Box 36, Folder 346)
  Virgin Gorda Property
- Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic (Box 36, Folder 347)
  Council member; Renovation for Inpatient; Purchase of property for parking garage in rear; Outpatient facilities to be constructed
- WPGH Radio (Box 36, Folder 348)
  Taping, Questions for the Chancellor